E R U

Ε Ρ S Н K Е

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

49, Lateef Aregbe Street, Ago Palace Way, Okota Road, Lagos State,

Nigeria.

emeruwajoseph@gmail.com

+234 (0) 8136595944; +234 (0) 7038682231 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/joseph-emeruwa

Github: github.com/iJosef

CAREER OBJECTIVE I am a full-stack developer with about 2 years of experience in software development. It is my wish to pursue a fulfilling career in a dynamic and challenging organization of standard repute that provides for individual development, relevant skill acquisition and realization of individual potentials. More so, I will also like to work with professionals in my field so I can contribute better and make more impact to this organization while improving my skills and experience as a developer.

QUALIFICATIONS

Diploma in Web Design & Development

Unique Computer Institute, Owerri, Imo State. 03/2017 – 08/2017

B.Tech in Environmental Technology

Federal University of Technology, Owerri, Imo State. 10/2010 – 12/2015

West African SSCE 'O' Levels

Santana Rhetoric International School, Aba, Abia State. 09/2004 – 07/2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Cavidel Limited, Magodo, Lagos State.

03/2020 - present

Responsibilities includes but not limited to maintaining and improving the existing projects while contributing to the development of new projects using Laravel and PHP.

WordPress Developer

Jetheights Services Limited, Ibadan, Oyo State, 01/2019 - 12/2019

As the in-house web designer, my responsibilities included but not limited to Designing and Maintaining client and company websites, Online Marketing, Updating contents on various online platforms owned by the company.

Subject Teacher, National Youth Services Corps Sacred Heart Secondary School Ode Oolo, Ibadan, 04/2018 – 03/2019 As a school teacher during my service year, my responsibilities included teaching Security Education in the junior secondary classes and ensuring students participation in class exercises while having private classes for those interested in programming.

Student Intern, Effluent Treatment Plant Assistant Technician Nigerian Bottling Company Plc, Owerri, Imo State, 06/2014 – 12/2014

As a student intern, my responsibilities included but not limited to recording the results of tests carried out on the wastewater to determine the pH of the wastewater, the dissolved oxygen, the phosphorus and nitrogen content, and treating the wastewater by means of screening, sedimentation and chlorination into the company's database.

IT SKILLS

Proficient in all major Microsoft Office applications.

Knowledge of programming languages and frameworks such as HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP and MySQL. As well as knowledge of Laravel framework. Knowledge of Content Management System software including Wordpress and Blogger.

Database Management System software such as WAMP and XAMPP. Knowledge of Git and Github.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Teamwork skills

Ability to work under pressure Ability to meet deadlines Commitment and determination Research skills

Attention to detail Independence

SPECIAL TRAININGS

Software Development Training

Startdotng, HNG Internship 6.0. 08/2019 – 11/2019

- Git Version Control System
- > Collaboration
- > Introduction to the use of Laravel framework

Youth Empowered Nigeria Workshop

Nigerian Bottling Company (NBC). 11/2017

- Business planning skills
- > Communication and Networking skills
- Life skills

ACHIEVEMENTS

Solid waste management policy in Federal University of Technology, Owerri - Member

Developer of <u>josef-dev.000webhostapp.com</u>, <u>josephemeruwa.netlify.com</u>, <u>wexchange.com.ng</u>, <u>dekingsells.com</u>, <u>vegeesdietry.com</u>, <u>foursevenstudios.com</u> President of Environmental and Beautification CDS group during service year. Finalist HNG Internship 6.0

LANGUAGE SKILLS English Language

Igbo Language

Programming

INTERESTS

Travelling Meeting People Playing Chess/Scrabble Reading

REFERENCES Available on request